Jacob Clapper

clapperpianist@gmail.com · Jamaica Plain, MA · <u>linkedIn</u> · <u>github.com</u> · <u>portfolio</u>

As a creative, focused, and diligent Software Engineer, I strive to develop full stack applications that are intuitive and efficient. My background as a teacher and pianist has given me the ability to manage and prioritize multiple obligations . I have developed necessary communication skills to collaborate as a team and also work independently. It is with this experience that I am able to build creative solutions that build community and increase productivity.

Skills JavaScript, Vanilla Javascript, React.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Heroku, Express, liquid, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python 3.7, Git, GitHub, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Trello, Postman, Canva

CLIENTS

Elias Dagher https://magnificent-tartufo-c4359b.netlify.app
All Souls Choir https://www.uubraintreemusic.org
Jacob Clapper https://jacobclapper.com

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Harmony Haven Github: Client API

August 2022

Hosted on Netlify

Wireframes and planned UI design of application using Canva

Developed an MVP before moving to final production

Utilized MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js to build a full stack application with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and API back-end and a front-end client Made frequent commits using Git control throughout the production of application Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections

Used seeded data for models

Freelancr Github: Client - API

August 2022

Hosted on Heroku

Wireframes and planned UI design of application using Canva

Developed an MVP before moving to final production

Utilized MERN to build a full stack application with CRUD operations with API back-end and a front-end client

Collaborated as a team making frequent commits using Git control throughout the production of application

Used seeded data for models and subdocuments

Music Lesson and Assignment Tracker github

July 2022

Wireframes and planned UI design of application using Canva Developed an MVP before moving to final production Utilized MERN to build a full stack application with CRUD operations Made frequent commits using Git control throughout the production of application Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections
Deployed the web application to a remote server using heroku

Memory Game github

June 2022

Used Vanilla Javascript, CSS3, and HTML5 and DOM manipulation to create a memory card matching game

Utilized Javascript and Vanilla Javascript in creating object oriented function

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

All Souls Unitarian Universalist Church,

Software Engineer, https://www.uubraintreemusic.org

September 2022-Current

Utilized MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js to build a full stack application with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and API back-end and a front-end client Deployed on Heroku, and domain hosted with Google

Continuous Integration and Development of front-end code and database

Music Director August 2014 - Current

Collaborate with the minister or other service leaders in the creation of worship services.

Choose anthems and hymns, in consultation with ministers/service leaders.

Provide piano music for the Sunday services September through June with one Sunday off per month.

Curry College, Collaborative Pianist/Private Music Instructor

September 2016 - 2020

Played for Choir Ensemble rehearsals and semester concerts

Taught keyboard skills such as sign reading, technique, music theory,

Introduced students to music relevant to the development of music history and piano technique.

Duxbury Public Schools, Collaborative Pianist/Lessons

August 2013 - June 2019

Concerts and Rehearsals (September 2013-June 2019) Music Director- Robert Judge Weekly rehearsals and yearly concerts for High School Choruses and Middle School Choruses: (High School- Chamber Singers, Concert Choir) (Middle School -6th Grade Chorus, 7/8th Mixed Chorus and ½ Concert Chorus)

Concerts- All Choral Night, Holiday Assemblies, Spring and Fall Concerts, and concerts at venues such as Carnegie Hall, Strathmore Hall, and Disney Springs in Orlando, Fl.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive (June 2022 - August 2022)

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 12-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Masters of Music *Piano Performance*, University of Florida (2013) Bachelors of Music *Piano Performance*, Texas A&M University-Commerce (2011)

Awards- Graduate Assistantship, University of Florida